Guide to the Law Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Law Family Papers
1806-1857
GEN MSS 1140
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.84
(8 boxes)
The Law Family Papers document aspects of the personal and professional life of Yale graduate and lawyer Samuel A. Law (1771-1845).
Law family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Law Family Papers were acquired by Yale University Library in 1929.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
This collection may be housed off-site at Yale's Library Shelving Facility (LSF). To determine if all or part of this collection is housed off-site please check the library’s online catalog, Orbis; material for which the location is given as "LSF" must be requested 36 hours in advance. Please consult with Beinecke Access Services for more information.
Arrangement
Arranged in one series: Series I. Correspondence and Other Papers, 1806-1857.
Samuel Andrew Law (1771-1845)
Samuel A. Law was born in Cheshire, Connecticut in 1771, the son of William Law and Mary Hotchkiss Law. He graduated from Yale College in 1792, attended the Litchfield Law School in 1793, and was admitted to the bar in 1795. In the following year, he founded a school which later became part of an Episcopal Academy of Cheshire. In 1797 he moved to Delaware County, New York, where he began a law practice and remained for the rest of his life.
Law married Sarah Sherman, and they had at least four sons: Jonathan Albion Law, Samuel A. Law, Stephen Dodd Law, and William Lyon Law. He died in Meredith, New York in 1845.
Scope and Contents
The Law Family Papers document aspects of the personal and professional life of Yale graduate and lawyer Samuel A. Law (1771-1845). Contents include family correspondence between Law and his brother, William Law, Jr.; his son Stephen Dodd Law; and other members of the Law family; letters to Law from others, including Timothy Brainerd and Jeremiah Day; and financial records, particularly records of the final estates and debts of several Law family members.
Families -- United States; Fathers and sons -- United States; Lawyers -- Connecticut; Lawyers -- United States -- Connecticut; Law family; Law, Jonathan Albion, 1819-; Law, Samuel Andrew, 1771-1845; Law, Samuel Andrew, 1816-; Law, Stephen D. (Stephen Dodd), 1820-1886; Law, William, approximately 1750-approximately 1835; Law, William, 1779-1856; Law, William Lyon, 1814-; Yale College (1718-1887)
- Correspondence and Other Papers, 1806-1857; Series I; 3.84; (8 boxes)
  - Samuel Andrew Law
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to father, William Law, 1806-1822 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to brother, Andrew Law, 1809-1840 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to brother, Jonathan Law, 1806-1843 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to brother, William Law, Jr., 1804-1844 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to brother-in-law, William Lyon, 1835-1840 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to son, Jonathan Albion Law, 1834 September 3 and 1840 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to son, Samuel A. Law, 1823-1843 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to son, Stephen Dodd Law, 1834-1841 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to son, William Lyon Law, and financial documents, 1825-1839 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to sisters and other family members, 1817-1839 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to Timothy G. Brainard, 1833-1839 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to Jeremiah Day and Benjamin Silliman, 1830-1839 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to Dr. F. T. Judson, 1839-1840 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to Silas Metcalf, 1835-1837 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to Amasa and Amasa J. Parker, 1838-1844 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters to others, 1813-1840 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Law, Samuel A. Letters and notes concerning the death of son, William Lyon Law, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Law, Samuel A. Records of children's schooling, 1831-1846 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Law, Samuel A. Financial records and other notes, 1832-1852 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Law, Samuel A. Petition to the State of Connecticut Superior Court and Deposition, circa 1841 and 1844 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Law, Samuel A. Orders left on going abroad, 1815 December (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Law, Samuel A. Honors and awards (Box 8 (Oversize), Folder 82)
  - William Law, Jr.
    - Law, William Jr. Letters to brother, Samuel A. Law, 1806-1819 (Box 2, Folder 24-29)
    - Law, William Jr. Letters to brother, Samuel A. Law, 1820-1844, undated (Box 3, Folder 30-37)
    - Law, William Jr. Letters to others, 1809-1853 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Law, William Jr. and Samuel A. Law: Financial and legal documents, 1817-1842 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Law, William Jr. Records of travel and other financial and legal documents, 1812-1840 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Stephen Dodd Law
    - Law, Stephen Dodd. Letters to father, Samuel A. Law, 1834-1841 (Box 4, Folder 41-44)
    - Law, Stephen Dodd. Letters to brothers, 1850-1857 (Box 4, Folder 45-48)
    - Law, Stephen Dodd. Financial records, 1834-1842 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Other Law family Members
    - Law, Andrew. Letters to brother, Samuel A. Law, 1808-1844 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Law, Jonathan (1784-1859). Letters to brother, Samuel A. Law, 1806-1843 (Box 5, Folder 51-53)
    - Law, Jonathan Albion (1812- ). Letters to parents, Samuel A. Law and Sarah Lyon Law, 1834-1838 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Law, Jonathan Albion (1812- ). Letters to father, Samuel A. Law, 1842 August 9, November 13 and 28 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Law, Jonathan Albion (1812- ). Financial records, 1840-1857 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Law, Samuel Andrew Jr. (1810- ). Letters to parents, Samuel A. Law and Sarah Lyon Law and legal document, 1824-1842 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Law, William (1750-1824). Letters to son, Samuel A. Law, 1809-1824 (Box 6, Folder 58-60)
    - Law, William (1750-1824). State of debt left upon his death (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Law, William Lyon (1808-1839). Letters to father, Samuel A. Law, and other family members, 1824-1839 (Box 6, Folder 62-64)
    - Law, William Lyon (1808-1839). Financial records, 1807-1837 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Law, William Lyon (1808-1839). Obituary in the Delaware Gazette, 1839 November 27 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Related Correspondence and Papers
    - Baird, Rev. William. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1839 November 4 and 14 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Brainand, Rev. Timothy G. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1831-1840 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Day, Jeremiah. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1830-1839 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Dwight, B. W. Letters and records of accounts with Samuel A. Law, 1820-1828 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Judson, Dr. F. T. Letters to Samuel A. Law and financial records for William Lyon Law, 1839-1840 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Law, Rev. Andrew. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1816-1820 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Linsley, James H. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1820-1823 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Lyon, Col. William. Legal and financial documents, including Declaration of Trust from Samuel A. Law, 1831 December 19 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Metcalf, Silas. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1835-1837 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Parker, Amasa and Amasa J. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1820-1844 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Williams, S. R. Letters to Samuel A. Law, 1839 October 17, 31, and November 25 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Letters from others to members of the Law family, 1813-1842 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Other papers relating to the Law family, 1806-1851 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Survey of farm for M. Osterhout, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Notes on the Law Family and Law Family papers, undated (Box 7, Folder 81)